

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com

www.LondonResearchInternational.com

Mr. Singh

London

NATIONALITY: UK & Canada, Overseas Citizen of India (Permanent Indian work visa)

SUMMARY

South Asia analyst experienced in political, regulatory, operational and security analysis for multinational corporations, aiding board level decisions for a \$1 bn tourism and gaming investment (Sri Lanka), a \$100 mn+ power infrastructure contract (India), and a \$200 mn pharmaceutical investment (India). Oxford MSc with published research on the Indian coal and solar sectors. Former producer of BBC television programmes with strong project management skills.

EDUCATION

University of Oxford Oxford

MSc Contemporary India Oct. 2008 - July 2009

University of Oxford Oxford

MSc Contemporary India Oct. 2008 - July 2009

Thesis: India's solar energy industry and the Indian government's stance at climate change negotiations.

- Modules include: Politics, International Relations, Political Economy, Environment, Human Development.
- University of Oxford scholarship in 2008/9 (5,000 GBP). Doctorate offer in 2009 from Dept. of Politics.
- **University of Bristol Bristol**

B.A. - First Class Honours, English Literature Oct. 1994 - June 1997

EMPLOYMENT RECORD/PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Analyst, India (Oxford University), Jan. 2014 – May 2014 London, New Delhi, Dhanbad

Political and stake-holder analysis of illegal coal trade in Jharkhand, India's major coal



Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com

www.LondonResearchInternational.com

producing state.

- Researched by high-level interviews with senior politicians, industry executives, union leaders.
- > Delivered an in depth study on political corruption for a major Oxford / UCL project on Indian democracy.

• Journalist, Aug. 2013 – Jan. 2014

London, India

- 3000 word reportage on India's coal thieves (Open Magazine, Jan. 2014) http://www.openthemagazine.com/article/nation/thieves-on-two-wheels
- > 1200 word edit of the above, (The Guardian, Sept. 2013)

• Control Risks Group

Analyst, South Asia (Global Risk Analysis, sub-contractor) Feb. 2013 – Aug. 2013 Analyst, South Asia (Global Risk Analysis, staff) Aug. 2011 – Feb. 2013 Singapore, London

- Bespoke analysis for Fortune 500 companies and a G7 government on regulation, politics, corruption, security.
- Extensive on the ground consulting with a diverse network in South Asia.
- > Strong presentational skills key speaker at Control Risks 'Risk Map' events in Delhi & Singapore, and seminars for MNCs on Indian manufacturing, and geo-politics of South Asian security. Video and audio clips available.

Institute of Defence Studies and Analyses (IDSA) New Delhi

Visiting Fellow Jan. 2011 - Jul. 2011

New Delhi

Analysis of India's solar energy policy, paper published in peer-reviewed journal Strategic Analysis.

• Major UK Political Party

Local Campaigns Organiser Feb. 2010 - June 2010

Ramsgate, England

Led a campaign team during the last British general election, in South Thanet constituency.



Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

 $\label{lemail:consultant@londonresearch international.com} \\ \underline{ www.LondonResearch International.com} \\ \\ \underline{ www.LondonResearch International.com} \\ \\ \\ \\ \underline{ www.LondonResearch International.com} \\ \\ \underline{ www.LondonResearch International.com} \\ \\ \underline{ www.LondonResearch International.com} \\ \underline{ www.LondonResearch International.$

• Independent Business & Public Policy Research

July 2009 - Dec. 2009

Bangalore, Delhi, Mumbai

- ➤ Interviewed CEOs of Indian solar photovoltaic firms Moser Baer Photovoltaic, Tata BP Solar, Hind High Vac.
- Co-authored papers in Economic & Political Weekly, and an Oxford Dept. of International Development book.

BBC & Channel Four Factual Television Producer London & Glasgow

- Producer, Assistant Producer, Researcher Sept. 1997 Dec. 2010
 - ➤ Produced and budgeted nationally broadcast BBC and Channel Four programmes, filming with leading figures including Jon Snow, Gordon Brown, Admiral Lord Alan West, Boris Johnson, Sir Martin Sorrell of WPP.

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS
n/a
PUBLICATIONS
n/a
LANGUAGES

English, Hindi